Guide to the Mark Dendy Papers, 1981-2013
American Dance Festival Archives
- Moving Images, 1986-2010 and undated, (5 boxes; 91 items)
  - Worlds Apart, October 15, 1995, #6, Betacam (Box 8)
  - Worlds Apart, October 15, 1995, #7, Betacam (Box 8)
  - Busride to Heaven, Mark Dendy, 1996, VHS (Box 7)
  - Worlds Apart, Dendy Dance & Theater, 1996, VHS (Box 7)
  - Winter Dance 1997, VHS (Box 7)
  - Les Biches (close-up), March 12, 1997, VHS (Box 7)
  - Les Biches, Pacific Northwest Ballet, Studio Rehearsal, June 4, 1997, VHS (Box 7)
  - Mark Dendy, Whitney Museum of American Art at Philip Morris, Performance on 42nd Presents MANY, A Three-Day Festival in Celebration of Ten Years of Performance, June 11-13, 1997, June 12, 1997, videotape (U-matic), 19:10 min. (Box 8)
  - First Chair, Second Chair, Mark Dendy, Whitney Museum at Philip Morris, Performance on 42nd/MANY, June 12, 1997, VHS, 19:10 min. (Box 7)
  - Ritual, The Nashville Ballet, 1997, VHS (Box 7)
    Choreography by Mark Dendy
  - Line Perspective, Ballet Wisconsin, March 7 and 8, 1998, VHS (Box 7)
    Chor: Mark Dendy
  - Swan Lake Premiere, Dortmund, February 27, 1999, VHS, PAL (Box 7)
  - Rock and Roll: Classic Sweet or I'm going to my room and I don't want to be disturbed (excerpted version), Mark Dendy Dance and Theater, Central Park SummerStage, July 23, 1999, DVCPRO, 25:08 min. (Box 9)
  - Rock and Roll: Classic Sweet or I'm going to my room and I don't want to be disturbed(excerpted version), Mark Dendy Dance and Theater, Central Park SummerStage, July 23, 1999, DVCPRO, 39 min. (Box 9)
  - Rock and Roll: Classic Sweet or I'm going to my room and I don't want to be disturbed, Mark Dendy Dance and Theater, Central Park SummerStage, July 22, 1999, VHS, 50 min. (Box 7)
  - Bible Stories, Mark Dendy, August 18, 2000, Alex, VHS (Box 7)
  - Night Moves, Jane Weiner, Bates Dance Festival: Alone & Together Faculty Concert, Bates College, June 21, 2001, VHS, broken (Box 9)
    Choreographed by Mark Dendy in collaboration with Lawrence Keigwin, Performed by Jane Weiner
  - Radio City Carnivale, March 2001, VHS, 16:25 min, broken (Box 7)
    Composite, Short and Long Versions
  - Mark Dendy, Pooh Kaye, Sally Silvers, Improv Festival, Movement Research at Danspace, December 3, 2004, VHS (Box 9)
  - The Magic Flute, Dir. Julie Taymor, Great Performances at the Met, January 24, 2007, DVD (Box 9)
  - Lecture Demonstration, Mark Dendy, Texas Woman's University Department of Dance, September 12, 2008, DVD (Box 9)
  - Festival Finale, Bates Dance Festival 2009, Bates College, August 8, 2009, DVD (Box 9)
  - Faith Healing, Jane Comfort and Company, 2010, DVD, 97 min. (Box 9)
  - Afternoon of the Faunes, Dendy Dancetheater, undated, DVD (Box 9)
  - Auguries One, Two, and Three, Pacific Northwest Ballet, 1, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Auguries One, Two, and Three, Pacific Northwest Ballet, 2, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Auguries One, Two, and Three, Pacific Northwest Ballet, undated, VHS (Box 10)
    Choreography by: Mark Dendy, Music by: Phillip Glass
  - Bardo, Drum, Dendy Dance & Theater, American Dance Festival, undated, VHS (Box 9)
  - Bugs of Durham, Mark Dendy, American Dance Festival, undated, VHS, 6:12 min. (Box 9)
  - Choreography by Mark Dendy, includes Symmetries (Pacific Northwest Ballet, 1994), Dream Analysis (Dendy Dance, 1998), Les Biches (Pacific Northwest Ballet, 1997), Ballet I (Nashville Ballet, 1990), Auguries (Pacific Northwest Ballet, 1998), VHS, PAL (Box 9)
  - Dendy Dance & Performance, Glenwood, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Dream Analysis, undated, VHS (Box 9)
  - Excerpts/Rep., undated, videotape (U-matic) (Box 9)
  - First Chair, Dendy/Schubert, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Francesca Page, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Franchesca Page, MD as Melba James, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Franchesca Page, Sane, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Go Down Moses by Sandy Sheets, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Juan Pablo Montes and Melissa Thompson, Texas, undated, DVD (Box 9)
  - Kinetic, Seattle, undated, VHS, broken (Box 10)
  - Les Biches, 10, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Les Biches, Pacific Northwest Ballet, 4, undated, VHS (Box 10)
    Choreography by Mark Dendy, Music by Francis Poulenc
  - Line Perspective, Rehearsal Tape, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Lippa's Wild Party, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Magic Flute, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Mark Dendy & Company, 151 1st Ave., #87, NYC 10003, undated, VHS (Box 9)
  - Movements 1 & 2, Wave, Garden, Reel, Chant, Hush, Dendy Dance, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Pippin, Goodspeed, B-Roll, undated, VHS (Box 9)
  - Ritual, Mark Dendy, undated, DVD (Box 9)
  - Ritual, The Nashville Ballet, undated, DVD (Box 9)
  - Swan Lake, undated, VHS (Box 9)
  - Symmetries, undated, VHS (Box 10)
    Composer: John Adams, Choreography: Mark Dendy
  - Symmetries, undated, VHS (Box 10)
    Dendy/Adams
  - Symmetries, 2, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Symmetries, 3, undated, VHS (Box 10)
  - Taboo, undated (2 tapes), VHS (Box 10)
  - Taboo, Broadway, full show, undated, DVD (Box 9)
  - Taboo, Dance Scenes, undated, DVD (Box 9)
  - Take a Walk on the Wild Side, from Classic Sweet, Mark Dendy, undated, VHS, 4:12 min. (Box 10)
  - Unlabeled, undated, VHS (Box 9)